Hi, I'm Prof Navarro.
مرحباً، أنا البروفيسور نافارو
>> And I'm Alex LeBon.
>> وأنا أليس ليبون.
>> All right, so what's on tap today?
>> كل الحق، فما هو على الصنبور اليوم؟
>> Loans, loans, and more loans.
>> القروض والقروض والمزيد من القروض
>> What kinda loans are we talking about?
>> ما نوع القروض التي نتحدث عنها؟
>> Well you name it, we will cover it.
>> حسنا يمكنك تسمية ذلك، ونحن سوف تغطي ذلك.
Mortgages, auto loans, lines of credit, you get the picture.
الرهن العقاري، قروض السيارات، خطوط الائتمان، تحصل على الصورة.
>> All right, what's our big take away?
>> كل الحق، ما هو لدينا اتخاذ كبير بعيدا؟
>> Simply, that if you understand the loan process.
>> ببساطة, أنه إذا كنت تفهم عملية القرض.
You'll get into that first home and fast car.
ستدخلين أول منزل وسيارة سريعة
And whatever else you have your eye on.
وأي شيء آخر لديك عينك عليه
A lot faster than if you are loan illiterate.
أسرع بكثير مما لو كنت قرضا أمييا.
>> And, as I understand it, a lot of it is a vernacular game.
>> و, كما أفهم, الكثير من هو لعبة العامية.
>> Right.
>> الحق.
You need to know about stuff like down payments, amortization schedules,
تحتاج إلى معرفة أشياء مثل المدفوعات الأولية، جداول الاستهلاك،
annuity formulas, liquidity, the really big difference between fixed and
صيغ الأقساط السنوية، السيولة، الفرق الكبير حقا بين
adjustable rate mortgages.
القروض العقارية الثابتة والقابلة للتعديل.
>> All right, that actually sounds pretty interesting, but
>> كل الحق، وهذا في الواقع يبدو مثيرا للاهتمام جدا، ولكن
before I turn you loose for part one, can I ask you something?
قبل أن تتحول لك فضفاضة للجزء الأول، هل يمكنني أن أسألك شيئا؟
>> Sure.
>> بالتأكيد.
>> Can you lend me a few bucks to my next paycheck?
>> هل يمكنك أن تقرضني بضعة دولارات لراتبي التالي؟
>> Got any collateral?
>> هل لديك أي ضمانات؟
>> Why do you ask?
>> لماذا تسأل؟
>> You'll have to view the lesson to find out.
>> سيكون لديك لعرض الدرس لمعرفة ذلك.
>> All right, off we go.
>> كل الحق، قبالة نذهب.
[MUSIC]
[ موسيقى]